thepointsguy.com 2014-12-23

# Privacy Policy / Your California Privacy Rights | The Points Guy

This post contains references to products from one or more of our advertisers. We may receive compensation when you click on links to those products. For an explanation of our Advertising Policy, [visit this page](http://thepointsguy.com/tpg-advertising-policy/).

PRIVACY POLICY / YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS

Last updated: December 16, 2013

This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, use and share information when you use our Services.  
The terms “we,” “us,” or “our” mean The Points Guy, a Delaware corporation, and its legal subsidiaries  
and affiliates. The term “Services,” means, collectively, various websites, applications, widgets, email  
notifications and other mediums, or portions of such mediums, through which you have accessed this  
Privacy Policy. By accessing or using our Services, you consent to the collection, transfer, manipulation,  
storage, disclosure and other uses of Your Information (collectively, “Use of Your Information”) as  
described in this Privacy Policy.

For purposes of this Privacy Policy, “Your Information” means information about you, which may be  
of a confidential nature and may include personally identifying information, medical and health history  
information, and/or financial information.

This Privacy Policy applies to our Use of Your Information as a result of you using our Services, and does  
not apply to the following:

• Information collected through mediums other than our Services;  
• Information collected through our Services where a separate privacy policy applies, such as a sweepstakes  
entry (you should refer to the official rules and privacy policy for each individual

sweepstakes for our specific policies regarding information sharing and disclosure pursuant to sweepstakes entry); or

• Information collected by any person or entity other than us, even if related to our Services (such as a third-party  
website, application, widget or lead form).

In addition to this Privacy Policy, our Services are also governed by our Terms of Use and any other  
documents referred to in this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use. These documents describe  
information that we collect from you or that you provide on or to the Services and how Your Information  
may be used and disclosed by us. They also describe the choices available to you regarding our Use of  
Your Information and how you can access and update Your Information. Please read this Privacy Policy  
and the Terms of Use carefully.

Information We Collect and Receive About You  
We might receive or collect several types of information about you, such as the information described

Information You Provide

The following are situations in which you may provide Your Information to us:

• When you fill out forms or fields through our Services;  
• When you sign up for any newsletters or other materials through our Services;  
• When you provide information to us through a third-party application, service or website;  
• When you communicate with us or request information about us or our Services, whether via  
• When you participate in online surveys;  
• When you participate in any of our marketing initiatives, including, contests, events, or  
• When you participate in forums or provide user generated content or submissions.

Information Third Parties Provide

We may collect information about you from sources other than you, such as from social media websites  
(i.e., Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter or others), blogs, other users and our business partners.

General Use and Preference Information

We may collect, receive and store information regarding your general use of our Services (such as details  
of how and when you used our Services, interactions with our Services, log in information, resources that  
you access, your Internet protocol address, your browser type, and your device type), as well as your  
preferences.

Device Information

When you use our Services through your computer, mobile phone or other device, we may collect  
information regarding and related to your device, such as hardware models and IDs, device type,  
operating system version, the request type, the content of your request and basic usage information  
about your use of our Services, such as date and time. In addition, we may collect information regarding  
application-level events and associate that with your account to provide customer service. We may also  
collect and store information locally on your device using mechanisms such as browser web storage and  
application data caches.

Location Information

If you enable the collection of location information on your device, then we may collect information about  
your actual location, such as your mobile device’s GPS coordinates. We may also use other technologies  
to determine your location (such as through the location of nearby Wi-Fi access points or cell towers), or  
obtain your location information from third parties.

Phone Numbers

We may collect your phone number in several ways. For example, we may collect your phone number:  
(i) if you submit your phone number to us through our Services; (ii) by capturing your phone number if you  
call us; or (iii) if a third party provides your phone number to us.

Cookies and Anonymous Identifiers

We and third parties use various technologies to collect and store information when you use our Services,  
including sending cookies, pixel tags or other anonymous identifiers to your device. “Cookies” are pieces  
of data stored on your computer, mobile phone or other device. A “pixel tag” is a type of technology  
placed within a website or email for the purpose of tracking activity, which is often used in combination  
with cookies. Other “anonymous identifiers” are random strings of characters used for the same purposes  
as cookies, such as with mobile devices where cookie technology is not available. These technologies  
help us know that you are logged on, provide you with features based on your preferences, understand  
when you are interacting with our Services, and compile other information regarding use of our Services.  
The information collected through these technologies, standing alone, cannot be used to determine  
your identity. Such information may, however, be combined in a way that makes it become personally  
identifiable information (i.e., information that can identify you). If this happens, we will treat the combined  
information as personally identifiable information.

Please note that, in most cases, you can remove or block cookies (such as by using the settings in your  
browser), but doing so may affect your ability to use our Services.

The use of tracking technologies by our service providers, technology partners or other third party assets  
(such as social media) on the Services is not covered by our Privacy Policy. These third parties may use  
cookies, clear gifs, images, and scripts to help them better manage their content on our Services. We do  
not have access or control over these technologies.

How We Use Information

We may make Use of Your Information for various lawful business purposes. Among others, these  
purposes may include using Your Information to:

\- Engage in customer support. For example, we might confirm and complete transactions  
requested by you, verify information you provide to us and provide you with administrative  
notices.

\- Contact you and provide you with information. For example, we might provide or contact you  
through telephone, email, postal or other communications with Service updates, promotional  
materials, surveys, offers, quotes, personalized information and other information from us or our  
business partners.

\- Analyze, improve and manage our Services and operations. For example, we might obtain  
feedback regarding our Services, understand and anticipate your needs and preferences, better  
understand your use of our Services, customize and tailor Service content and advertising,  
improve our marketing and promotional efforts, engage in statistical analysis and provide  
feedback to our vendors, advertisers and other third parties.

\- Resolve problems and disputes, and engage in other legal and security matters. For example,  
we may use Your Information to comply with, monitor compliance with and enforce this Privacy  
Policy, our Terms of Use and any other applicable agreements and policies, meet other legal and  
regulatory requirements, and to protect the security and integrity of our Services.

How We Disclose Information

General Disclosure of Your Information

We may disclose Your Information:

\- To any person who, in our reasonable judgment, is authorized to receive Your Information as  
your agent, including as a result of your business dealings with that person (for example, your  
attorney);

\- To our third-party vendors so that they may provide support for our internal and business  
operations, including for the handling of data processing, data verification, data storage, surveys,  
research, internal marketing, delivery of promotional, marketing and transaction materials,  
and our Services’ maintenance and security. These companies are authorized to Use Your  
Information only as necessary to provide these services to us and are contractually obligated to  
keep Your Information confidential;

\- To third parties such as insurance providers when you use our Services to request a quote,  
services, or information from one or more of those third parties (“Requested Service Providers”),  
such as by clicking “get your quotes” or other similar buttons at the end of a form;

\- To third parties when you engage in certain activities through our Services that are sponsored  
by them, such as purchasing products or services offered by a third party, electing to receive  
information or communications from a third party, or electing to participate in contests,  
sweepstakes, games or other programs sponsored, in whole or in part, by a third party. When  
we disclose Your Information to these third parties, Your Information will become subject to the  
information use and sharing practices of the third party, and the third party will not be restricted by  
this Privacy Policy with respect to its use and further sharing of Your Information;

\- To third parties that are interested in contacting you or providing offers to you that may be related  
to our Services or about products or services you may find of interest;

\- As required by law or ordered by a court, regulatory, or administrative agency;

\- As we deem necessary, in our sole discretion, if we believe that you are violating any applicable  
law, rule or regulation, or are otherwise interfering with another’s rights or property, including,  
without limitation, our rights or property;

\- If requested by authorities in the event of any act of terrorism or instance of local, regional or  
national emergency;

\- To enforce our Terms of Use, this Privacy Policy, and any other applicable agreements and  
policies;

\- To enforce or protect our rights;

\- In connection with a Business Transfer, as defined below (see Business Transfers below); and

\- To our affiliated companies (i.e., companies under common control or management with us).

If you do not want Your Information shared as described above, then you should not  
provide us with Your Information.

Requests for Quotes and Services from Requested Service Providers

As noted above, we may share Your Information with Requested Service Providers when you  
use our Services to request a quote, services or information from one or more third parties  
(a “Request”). IF YOU SUBMIT A REQUEST, REQUESTED SERVICE PROVIDERS MAY  
CONTACT YOU DIRECTLY WITH QUOTES VIA MAIL, TELEPHONE, TEXT MESSAGE, FAX,  
EMAIL AND OTHER MEANS OF COMMUNICATION. YOU MAY RECEIVE TELEMARKETING  
CALLS AS A CONSEQUENCE OF SUBMITTING A REQUEST THROUGH OUR SERVICES,  
EVEN IF YOU ARE ON THE NATIONAL DO NOT CALL REGISTRY OR ANY OTHER DO NOT  
CALL REGISTRY.

If you are matched with Requested Service Providers, you expressly consent to the Requested Service  
Providers conducting any research necessary to provide you with quotes for your Request. Requested  
Service Providers may need to share Your Information to conduct such research. As an example, if  
you request insurance quotes, consumer reports may be ordered in connection with your insurance  
application. Such reports may provide information that may assist in determining eligibility for insurance  
and the price you may be charged for insurance. Consumer reports may also be used for updates,  
renewal or extensions of this insurance. In addition, insurance companies may use third parties in  
connection with the development of a “insurance score” for you. If you do not want Requested Service  
Providers to conduct necessary research to provide you with a quote for your Request, then you  
should not submit a Request.

Please note that if you submit a Request through our Services and we share Your Information as  
described above in connection with your Request, you will not have the opportunity to opt out of  
the disclosure of Your Information in connection with that Request.

Aggregation and De-Personalization

We may take Your Information and de-indentify it either by combining it with information about  
other individuals (aggregating Your Information with information about other individuals), or by  
removing characteristics (such as your name) that make the information personally identifiable to  
you (de-identifying Your Information). We reserve the right to share, loan, rent, sell, or otherwise  
disclose such information to third parties at any time, for any lawful purpose, without notice or  
compensation to you.

Sharing with Friends

If the Services contains any functionality allowing you to send content to a friend, then please be aware  
that: (a) we may display your email address to your friend; and (b) we may use information you provide  
about your friend to facilitate the communication and as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy.

Sweepstakes

If you are submitting information to us pursuant to a sweepstakes entry, we reserve the right to share,  
loan, rent, sell or otherwise disclose the information that you submit with third parties at any time, for any  
lawful purpose without notice or compensation to you. Participation in these sweepstakes is completely  
voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose Your Information. Please refer to  
the official rules and privacy policy for each individual sweepstakes for our specific policies regarding  
information sharing and disclosure pursuant to that sweepstakes entry.

Circumvention of Security Measures

We cannot ensure that Your Information will only be disclosed as described in this Privacy Policy. No  
method of transmission or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, and we cannot guarantee  
absolute security. Additionally, by way of example (without limiting the foregoing), we may be forced to  
disclose Your Information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances, or third parties  
may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. Therefore, notwithstanding  
anything to the contrary within this Privacy Policy, our Terms of Use or any other applicable agreement  
or policy, you use our Services at your own risk and we do not promise or guarantee, and you should not  
expect, that Your Information will always remain private. In the event that an unauthorized third party  
compromises our security measures, we will not be responsible for any damages directly or indirectly  
caused by an unauthorized third party’s ability to view, use or disseminate Your information.  
Business Transfers

We specifically and expressly reserve the right to disclose, lease, sell, assign or transfer Your Information  
collected through our Services, and any of our databases, together with any personally identifiable  
information contained in such databases, to third parties in connection with a Business Transfer. A  
“Business Transfer” means a share or asset sale, acquisition, merger, consolidation, reorganization, spin-  
off, bankruptcy or other corporate change involving us and/or our affiliates, even if the Business Transfer  
is only being contemplated and regardless of whether the Business Transfer relates to a part or a whole  
of our business. Nothing in this Privacy Policy is intended to interfere with our ability to transfer all or part  
of our business, equity, and/or assets (including our Services) to an affiliate or independent third party at  
any time, for any lawful purpose, without compensation to you.

Children’s Information

You must be at least 13 years of age to register with or use certain portions of the Services. The  
Services are not intended for children under 13 years of age. No one under 13 years of age may  
provide any personal information to or on the Services. We do not knowingly collect personal  
information from children under 13. If you believe that we may have any information from or  
about a child, please contact us at webmaster@bankrate.com.

Network Advertising

From time to time, we may participate in or use advertising networks, such as third-party  
advertising servers, advertising agencies, technology vendors and research firms. We may use  
these third-party advertising networks for marketing, advertising and promotional purposes, as  
well as to serve advertisements to you. Advertising networks often gather data about consumers  
who view advertisements to make inferences about a consumer’s interests and preferences,  
which enables their computers to deliver advertisements directly targeted to the consumer’s  
specific interests. This practice is often referred to as “online behavioral advertising.” For  
example, a third-party advertising network might collect the type of Internet browser you use, the  
type of computer operating system you use, the domain name of a website you visit, whether or  
not you visit specific pages of a website, the location of your Internet service provider’s presence,  
the date and time of a visit to a website and other interactions between you and a website.  
Please see the “Online Behavioral Advertising” subsection of Choices About How We Use and  
Collect Your Information below to read about how you can prevent certain third-party advertising  
networks from collecting information about you.

User Generated Content

We offer publicly accessible blogs and other interactive media through our Services. To request removal  
of Your Information from our blog or community forum, contact us at webmaster@bankrate.com. In  
some cases, we may not be able to remove Your Information, in which case we will let you know if we are  
unable to do so and why.

Some comment areas are managed by a third party application that may require you to register to post  
a comment. We do not have access or control of the information posted to the blog. You will need to  
contact or login into the third party application if you want the personal information that was posted to  
the comments section removed. To learn how the third party application uses your information, please  
review their privacy policy.

You are responsible for any content, including personal information, that you contribute to be published  
or displayed (“posted”) on our Services, or that you transmit to other users of our Services (collectively,  
“User Generated Content”). Your User Generated Content is posted on and transmitted to other users  
of our Services at your own risk. We cannot control the actions of other users of our Services with whom  
you may choose to share your User Generated Content. We are not responsible for circumvention of  
any privacy settings or security measures of our Services. As a result, we cannot and do not guarantee  
that your User Generated Content will not be viewed by unauthorized persons. You understand and  
acknowledge that, even after removal, copies of your User Generated Content may remain viewable in  
cached and archived pages, or might have been copied or stored by other Service users. Proper access  
and use of information provided through our Services, including User Generated Content, is governed by  
our Terms of Use.

Social Media Widgets

Our Services may include social media features, such as the Facebook Like button or interactive mini-  
programs that run on our Services. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are  
visiting, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Your interactions with these  
features are governed by the privacy policy of the third party providing it.  
Choices About How We Use and Disclose Your Information

We strive to provide you with choices regarding the personal information you provide to us. Below are  
some mechanisms that provide you with control over certain information:

\- Cookies. If you do not wish us to collect cookies, you may set your browser to refuse cookies,  
or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If you do so, please note that some parts of our  
Services may then be inaccessible or may not function properly.

\- Email Offers from Us. If you do not wish to receive email offers or newsletters from us, you can  
opt out of receiving email information from us (other than emails related to the completion of  
your registration, correction of user data, change of password and other similar communications  
essential to your transactions through our Services) by using the unsubscribe process at the  
bottom of the email.

\- Online Behavioral Advertising. Certain third-party advertising networks that deliver behavioral  
advertising are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”). You can prevent NAI  
member companies from collecting preference data about you by clicking here and following  
the NAI’s directions. Note that if you opt out through the NAI, you will still receive advertising. In  
addition, if you opt out through the NAI and later delete your cookies, use a different browser or  
buy a new computer, you will need to renew your opt out choice.

Information You Disclose to Third Parties

You may be presented with an opportunity to receive information and/or marketing offers from third  
parties in connection with our Services. All information you disclose to such third parties will be subject to  
the privacy policy and practices of such third parties. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and  
practices of such third parties and, therefore, you should review the privacy policies and practices of such  
third parties prior to disclosing information to them. If you later decide that you no longer want to receive  
communications from a third party, you will need to contact that third party directly.

Links to Third-Party Websites

Our Services, as well as the email messages sent with respect to our Services, may contain links or  
access to websites operated by third parties that are beyond our control. For example, if you click to  
apply for a product such as a credit card through our Services, you may be linked to a third-party website  
to complete an application. Links or access to third parties from our Services are not an endorsement  
by us of such third parties, or their websites, applications, products, services, or practices. We are not  
responsible for the privacy policy, terms and conditions, practices or the content of such third parties.  
These third-parties may send their own cookies to you and independently collect data. If you visit or  
access a third-party website, application or other property that is linked or accessed from our Services,  
we encourage you to read any privacy statements and terms and conditions of that third party before  
providing any personally identifiable information. If you have a question about the terms and conditions,  
privacy policy, practices or contents of a third party, please contact the third party directly.

Third Party Widgets and Plug-ins

Our Services include social media features, such as the Facebook Like button, links to our various social  
media pages and widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our  
Services. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may  
set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either  
hosted by a third party or hosted directly through our Services. Your interactions with these features are  
governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

Operation of our Services in the United States

Our Services are operated in the United States. If you are located in the European Union, Canada or  
elsewhere outside of the United States, please be aware that any information you provide to us will  
be transferred to the United States. By using our Services or providing us with Your Information, you  
consent to this transfer.

Changes to this Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to update, amend and/or change this Privacy Policy at any time in our sole  
discretion. Amendments will take effect immediately upon us posting the updated Privacy Policy on  
our Services. You are encouraged to revisit this Privacy Policy from time to time in order to review any  
changes that have been made. The date on which this Privacy Policy was last updated will be noted  
immediately above this Privacy Policy. Your continued access and use of our Services following the  
posting of any such changes shall automatically be deemed your acceptance of all changes.

Contacting Us

If you have questions or concerns about our privacy practices or wish to make a request regarding Your  
Information, please contact us at info@thepointsguy.com.

SPECIAL NOTIFICATION FOR CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS – YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS

Individuals who are residents of California and have provided their personally identifiable information  
to us may request information regarding our disclosures, if any, of their personally identifiable  
information to third parties for direct marketing purposes. Such requests must be submitted to us at  
info@thepointsguy.com or in writing at:

The Points Guy  
1815 Purdy Ave  
Miami Beach Fl  
33139

California privacy rights requests must include the reference “Request for California Privacy Information”  
on the subject line and in the body of the message and must include the email address or mailing  
address, as applicable, for us to send our response. This request may be made no more than once  
per calendar year. We reserve the right not to respond to requests submitted other than to the address  
specified above.

Disclaimer: The responses below are not provided or commissioned by the bank advertiser. Responses have not been reviewed, approved or otherwise endorsed by the bank advertiser. It is not the bank advertiser's responsibility to ensure all posts and/or questions are answered.
